PRANAV NARAHARI

■ naraharipranav@gmail | **८** (508) 410 - 6115 | **۞** github.com/pnav1023 | **th** linkedin.com/in/pranavnarahari

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROFESSIONAL

Software engineer with a unique blend of technical expertise and entrepreneurial drive, primed for startup environments. Hands on experience designing, developing, implementing, and enhancing features and components for diverse applications. Introduce improvements and solutions to drive application performance/usability while simplifying internal processes by applying skills in a variety of programming/scripting languages, tools, operating systems, and emerging technologies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

 $Solidity \cdot Smart\ Contracts \cdot Web3 \cdot React.js \cdot TypeScript \cdot Python \cdot Java \cdot SQL \cdot AWS \cdot Fullstack \cdot Infrastructure$

WORK EXPERIENCES

AI Coder @ Outlier AI, Inc.

Apr 2024 - Present

- Developing scripts, assessing AI responses, and evaluate colleagues' prompts to ensure quality ML model performance.
- Coding solutions using Swift, Python, Java, JavaScript, and more

Freelance Software Consultant

Mar 2024 - Present

- Developing services to allow users to **create blockchain backed contracts using zero code**.
- Leading UI efforts using TypeScript, MongoDB, and Rust. Currently focused on creating friction-less escrow solutions.
- Leading teams to secure first paying customer and revamping entire web tools (2100+ lines of code changed for License Logic). Eliminated bugs, improved user interface (UI) and user experience (UX), and enhanced functionality.
- Clients: Selfient, LMSW cheatsheet for Sashi Inc., Licence Logic

Software Engineer @ Citizens

June 2021 - Feb 2024

- During a substantial digital transformation (migration of hundreds of applications from on-prem to the cloud) and I was tasked with automating this process. The company was also looking to update its internal cloud training tools.
- Owned internal on-prem to cloud migration service and was the sole developer for cloud training API
- Employed ReactJS to quickly spin up UIs per internal application team specs, using Nunjucks and YAML for templating, utilized Typescript for data processing + API integration, and leveraged AWS Lambda, AWS Layers, and Python for backend development
- Drove time to migration down from 3 weeks to 30 mins with our automation. Cloud training tools enhancements: automated creation of a web IDE, email reminders, and programmatic AWS EC2 deletion

Software Engineer @ Mathematica Policy Research

May 2020 - Aug 2020

- Launched the redesign of app navigation for major devices and dynamically re-adjust based on the browser size.
- Utilized Vue.js for the app framework, Tailwind CSS for consistency and optimization in page styling, HTML for the restructuring of the navigation menu, TypeScript to add dynamic functionality, and GitHub for version control
- Presented a fully function UI fulfilling requirements of the customer, including low latency, intuitive customer experience, and industry-standard code practices

Software Engineer @ Kenway Consulting

Jan 2020 - May 2020

- While rapidly growing, the firm sought reorganization of its technical architecture and re-evaluation of its tech stack
- Led reorganization of company's data systems, redesign of data processing code, and tested and validated code changes
- Enhanced MS SQL Server proficiency by improving in all SQL query selectors and clauses to retrieve and modify data from database, developed server code in C#, and tested and validated with unit tests and manual test plans
- Eliminated data conflicts and consolidated all tables involving internal data, refactored server code to map data to new databases, and maximized code coverage with various forms of testing

EDUCATION

Bachelors in Computer Science at University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign | Graduated Spr. 2021 | GPA: 3.53 PROJECTS

dnAI, Python AI Chatbot

July 2024

- Personalized chat assistant leveraging AI to recommend certain supplements based on user's genetics
- Utilized Selenium and Python for scraping, Streamlit for UI, Ngrok for hosting, and Epsilon-ai as the LLM.

Chess3.0, Web-3.0 React.js App

May 2023

- React. is app leveraging the ETH network to store game state + players. Utilized solidity and Eth smart contracts
- Leveraged TDD (Test Driven Development), hardhat local blockchain, and manually tested using MetaMask.